So far in this course, when you've written SQL queries in the web-based
حتى الآن في هذه الدورة التدريبية، عند كتابة استعلامات SQL في المحرر المستند إلى الويب،
editor, we've hidden away the mechanism that actually connects to a database and
قمنا بإخفاء الآلية التي تتصل فعليًا بقاعدة بيانات
runs your queries.
وتدير استعلاماتك.
Some place back here, there's actually a database running those queries.
في مكان ما ف الخلف هنا، توجد في الواقع قاعدة بيانات تشغيل هذه الاستعلامات.
Now let's open up this box and see how it actually works.
والآن دعونا نفتح هذا المربع ونرى كيف يعمل بالفعل.
Behind our web server,
خلف خادم الويب الخاص بنا،
we're running Python code that connects to a SQLite database using DB-API calls.
نقوم بتشغيل كود Python الذي يتصل بقاعدة بيانات SQLite باستخدام استدعاءات واجهة برمجة تطبيقات قاعدة البيانات.
The Python DB-API isn't the library.
واجهة برمجة تطبيقات قاعدة بيانات Python ليست مكتبة.
It's a standard for
إنها معيار لمكتبات Python
Python libraries that let's your code connect to databases.
التي تتيح لك توصيل الكود بقواعد البيانات.
There are dozens of different libraries for
وتوجد العشرات من المكتبات المختلفة
different database systems that follow this standard.
لأنظمة قواعد البيانات المختلفة التي تتبع هذا المعيار.
The standard specifies what functions you'll call to connect to a database,
ويحدد المعيار الدوال التي ستقوم باستدعائها للاتصال بقاعدة بيانات،
to send queries, and to get results.
لإرسال استعلامات والحصول على نتائج.
So, if you learn the DB-API functions,
وبالتالي، إذا تعلمت دوال واجهة برمجة تطبيقات قاعدة البيانات،
you can apply that knowledge with any database system.
يمكنك حينها تطبيق هذه المعرفة على أي نظام قاعدة بيانات.
Although the details of what each database can do are different,
رغم أن تفاصيل ما يمكن لكل قاعدة بيانات القيام به مختلفة،
adapting Python code from one to another is quite straightforward.
إلا أن تكيف كود Python من قاعدة بيانات لآخري أمر بسيط للغاية.
But each database system has its own library.
ومع ذلك، لكل نظام قاعدة بيانات مكتبة خاصة به.
And as you can see, some of the library names are a little bit different from
وكما ترون، فإن بعض أسماء المكتبات تختلف قليلًا
the names of the database systems that we work with.
عن أسماء أنظمة قواعد البيانات التي نتعامل معها.
For exercises in the browser, we use the sqlite3 library.
في تمارين المستعرض، نستخدم مكتبة sqlite3.
When you run database code on your own machine for
عندما تقوم بتشغيل كود قاعدة البيانات على جهازك الخاص
this course though, you'll be using the psycopg2 library,
لهذه الدورة التدريبية، فستستخدم مكتبة psycopg2،
which let's your code talk to the PostgreSQL database.
التي تتيح للكود الخاص بك بالتحدث إلى قاعدة بيانات PostgreSQL.